[music]
[音乐]
Hello and welcome to section 4 of lesson 2.
您好，欢迎来到第2课的第4节。
In this part we're going to look at the
在这一部分中，我们将研究
various different places where you can create stream
您可以在其中创建流的各个不同地方
source from the classes and methods available
源于可用的类和方法
in JDK 8. If you do
在JDK 8中。
a complete analysis of the JDK 8 libraries you'll find
您会发现对JDK 8库的完整分析
actually 95 methods in 23 classes that return a stream,
实际上，有23个类中的95个方法返回了流，
but not all of them are actually stream sources because a lot of
但并非所有这些实际上都是流源，因为很多
them are actually intermediate operations in the Stream interface.
它们实际上是Stream接口中的中间操作。
You remember the stream intermediate operation is one that
您还记得流中间操作是
takes as input a stream and returns as output a stream.
将流作为输入，并将流作为输出返回。
So we don't actually use those as stream sources.
因此，我们实际上并不将其用作流源。
For ones that are usable as practical stream sources
对于可用作实际流源的那些
there are 71 methods in 15 classes that you can use.
您可以使用15个类中的71种方法。
And what we do in this part of the lesson is go through
在本节课中，我们要做的是
but most days of the week we actually go through with most with them.
但实际上一周中的大多数日子我们都会与他们一起经历大部分。
In terms of the collection interface we've
关于收集界面，我们已经
already seen this used, where we have a Collection
已经看到了这个用过的，我们有一个Collection
and we want to create a stream source, we call Stream.
我们要创建一个流源，我们称其为Stream。
And what that will do is provide a sequential stream of
而这将提供一个连续的
all the elements in that collection. If we want to create
该集合中的所有元素。如果我们要创建
parallel stream then we use the parallel stream
并行流，然后我们使用并行流
method. So that's very straightforward, if we want a sequential stream we
方法。所以这很简单，如果我们想要一个顺序流，我们
call stream,if we
呼叫流，如果我们
want parallel stream we call parallel stream that will create parallel stream
想要并行流，我们称为并行流，它将创建并行流
elements in the collection and how that actually works underneath
集合中的元素及其在下面的实际工作方式
is using the fore-join framework. We're going to talk about this more and
正在使用前连接框架。我们将进一步讨论这一点，
see more detail about this
查看有关此的更多详细信息
in lesson 3 when we talk about parallel streams
在第3课中，当我们谈论并行流时
specifically, so we'll come back to that later in
具体来说，所以我们稍后再讲
lesson 3. The
第三课
arrays class has a method called Stream because
arrays类有一个称为Stream的方法，因为
if you think about it an array is a collection of data, so it's logical that
如果您考虑一下，数组就是数据的集合，那么逻辑上
we would want to be able to create a stream from it,
我们希望能够从中创建一个流，
but because it is not a collection in the sense that the collections API
但是因为它不是集合API的集合
we can't just call stream on that. So in this case
我们不能只是在此调用流。所以在这种情况下
what we need to do is use the static methods in the Arrays
我们需要做的是在数组中使用静态方法
class and call stream where we pass
我们通过的课程和通话流
array as a parameter to that and we get back to stream,
数组作为参数，我们回到流中，
which is the stream elements in that array.
这是该数组中的流元素。
This will provide a sequential stream; there is no equivalent
这将提供一个顺序流；没有对等的东西
parallel stream from this, although again as we'll see in lesson 3 you can
并行流，尽管正如我们在第3课中看到的那样，
convert
兑换
a serial stream into a parallel stream without any problem.
从串行流到并行流没有任何问题。
There are some overloaded methods
有一些重载的方法
for different types if you want to be type-specific, so there is double,
如果您想针对特定类型使用不同的类型，则有两种类型，
int, long, and object available for that,
int，long和可用于此的对象，
depending on what the values that are stored in the array that you want to create a stream
取决于要创建流的数组中存储的值
from. The files class has
从。文件类具有
several useful new methods which can be used to create
可以用来创建几种有用的新方法
a stream source and we saw an example of the
流源，我们看到了一个示例
first one earlier on when we talked about BiPredicate
我们谈论BiPredicate时的第一个
in terms of the new functional interfaces and what
在新功能接口方面以及
find will do is, it will take a Path, which is a point in the file system
查找将要做的是，它将采用路径，这是文件系统中的一个点
where you're looking for particular
您正在寻找的地方
files; it takes a BiPredicate,
文件它需要一个BiPredicate，
which will enable you to define using Lambda expression
这将使您能够定义使用Lambda表达式
how you want to identify the files you're interested in
您如何识别感兴趣的文件
and that can be based on things like the size of name, and so on
可以基于名称的大小等
and also FileVisitOption to say we follow links or not.
以及FileVisitOption表示我们是否遵循链接。
There is the ability to create list of
有创建列表的能力
all files from specific point in your file system, so you pass the
来自文件系统中特定点的所有文件，因此您将
path as the parameter to list and that will give you a stream of
路径作为要列出的参数，这将为您提供
entries from given directory.
给定目录中的条目。
Lines is a very useful method, again what that will do is
线条是一种非常有用的方法，同样要做的是
take a point, a parameter which is a path
取一点，这是路径的参数
entry into your file system, which is a file and then
进入文件系统，它是一个文件，然后
lines will return you a stream, which are the lines of
行将返回一个流，这是
text in that file. You can process those as a stream into
该文件中的文本。您可以将它们作为流处理
all sorts of things with that and then lastly there's a
各种各样的东西，最后有一个
walk method, which takes a Path and then will
walk方法，它需要一个Path然后
do file walk based on that path and returning you a stream of file
根据该路径进行文件遍历并返回文件流
references using the walk
步行参考
method and then also whether you want to
方法，然后是否要
follow links or not. Random numbers.
跟随链接与否。随机数。
There are three classes which closely related:
有三类密切相关：
There's Random, ThreadLocalRandom and SplittableRandom depending on how you
根据您的方式，有Random，ThreadLocalRandom和SplittableRandom
actually want to use
实际想使用
random number generation in your code.
您代码中的随机数生成。
I won't go into details this here, but it's worth looking at
在这里我不会详细介绍，但是值得一看
the class documentation to see what the differences are between these.
类文档，以了解它们之间的区别。
From a stream point of view they're all exactly the same.
从流的角度来看，它们都是完全相同的。
We can produce either an infinite stream of
我们可以产生无限的
random numbers or we can produce a finite stream, where we can specify how
随机数，或者我们可以产生有限的流，我们可以在其中指定
many numbers we want
我们想要很多数字
in that stream. There are versions for
在那流中。有一些版本
ints, their versions for doubles and versions for longs. So we can
int，它们的版本为double，longs的版本。所以我们可以
create ramdom numbers as integers, doubles or longs and then there are four versions of
将随机数创建为整数，双精度或长整型，然后有四个版本的
each of those where we can specify whether
每个我们可以指定是否
we want finite or infinite stream of ints
我们想要有限或无限的整数流
and then we can also specify whether we want to use a seed
然后我们还可以指定是否要使用种子
to initialize that stream of random numbers.
初始化该随机数流。
So what we end up with is four different versions for
因此，我们最终得到了四个不同的版本
each int, double, and long which gives us
每个int，double和long都使我们
12 stream sources for
12个流源
each random number class because there are 3 ramdom number classes that's
每个随机数类别，因为有3个随机数类别
36 different ways of creating stream source
创建流源的36种不同方式
just from random numbers, so when I talked about numbers at the beginning
只是随机数，所以当我在一开始谈论数字时
36 of the the possible sources of streams
流的36种可能来源
are from random number generation.
来自随机数生成。
A few miscellaneous classes and methods.
一些杂类和方法。
For compressed files both JarFile and Zipfile
对于压缩文件，JarFile和Zipfile
now have a stream method, which returns a stream,
现在有一个stream方法，它返回一个流，
which are the file objects, related to the
与文件相关的文件对象
contents of the compressed archive. So that will extract the
压缩档案的内容。这样就可以提取
individual files and give you a file reference as an element in the stream
单个文件，并为您提供文件引用作为流中的元素
and then you can map that if you want to whatever values and so on.
然后可以将其映射为任意值，依此类推。
But the BufferedReader has lines method; this is very much the same as in the files class.
但是BufferedReader有lines方法；这与files类非常相似。
So that if you have BufferedReader associated with some source, whether it's a
因此，如果您将BufferedReader与某个源关联，则无论它是
network connection or a
网络连接或
serial port or something like that then you can
串口或类似的东西，那么你可以
have a stream of lines text that are being provided by
具有由提供的行文本流
whatever the BufferedReader is connected to.
无论BufferedReader连接到什么。
In pattern there is a new method called splitAsStream.
在模式中，有一个称为splitAsStream的新方法。
This essentially does the same thing at the split method;
这实际上在split方法上做同样的事情。
the split method returns an array of
split方法返回一个数组
strings, which match the particular pattern that we're interested in.
字符串，与我们感兴趣的特定模式匹配。
In the case of splitAsStream rather returning an array, it
在splitAsStream而不是返回数组的情况下，它
returns a stream, so that we can process that
返回一个流，以便我们可以处理
in whatever way we want to do. A couple of
以我们想做的任何方式。几个
other miscellaneous classes that we have. This CharSequence has
我们拥有的其他杂类。这个CharSequence有
two methods in it: one is chars, which will return a stream
其中有两种方法：一种是chars，它将返回一个流
which are the char values of that charSequence
这是该charSequence的char值
as ints, as a primitive stream and then there's also
作为整数，作为原始流，然后还有
code points which will return a stream
代码点将返回流
which is the code point values for that sequence.
这是该序列的代码点值。
and finally BitSet has a method called stream,
最后，BitSet有一个称为stream的方法，
which will return you a stream of the indices of the 00:07:52,680 --&gt; 00:07:58,600 different bits in that bit set which are set.
它将返回给您该位集中的131 00：07：52,680-&gt; 00：07：58,600不同位的索引流。
There are a number of static methods on the Stream
流上有很多静态方法
interface itself. And as I said
接口本身。正如我所说
in JDK 8 we now have the ability to include static method in interfaces, so
在JDK 8中，我们现在可以在接口中包含静态方法，因此
this is a good example where we've used that. You can take
这是我们使用它的一个很好的例子。你可以采取
two streams and you can concatenate them. And there's no way of merging
两个流，您可以将它们串联起来。而且没有合并的方法
streams, in the sense if taking
流，从某种意义上讲
one element from one stream then another element from different stream
一个流中的一个元素，然后是不同流中的另一个元素
and alternating that. You can concatenate two streams
并交替进行。您可以连接两个流
using concat and providing 2 streams. There is also the ability to provide an empty
使用concat并提供2个流。也可以提供空白
stream.
流。
I must admit I really don't know what the purpose of that is,
我必须承认我真的不知道这样做的目的是什么，
since I don't know why you would want an empty stream because there's nothing to
因为我不知道为什么你会想要一个空的流，因为没有什么可
process, but anyway, it's there
过程，但是无论如何，它在那里
should you find a use for it. There is
你应该找到它的用途吗？有
an of method, which will create a stream
of方法，将创建一个流
from a set of values and issues is that varargs syntax,
从一组值和问题来看是varargs语法，
so you can either pass a single value, you can pass a
因此您可以传递一个值，也可以传递一个
set of comma separated values or, because the varargs syntax will convert
一组用逗号分隔的值，或者，因为varargs语法将转换
the comma-separated values into an array
将逗号分隔的值放入数组
of values you too can pass
您也可以通过的价值观
something which generates an array values and that will then create a
生成数组值的东西，然后将创建一个
stream from that. You can create
从那流。您可以创建
ranges of values for
的值范围
integers. If you want to create, in effect like a loop,
整数。如果您想要创建（实际上就像一个循环），
but obviously it's not a loop, because we don't do explicit loops in terms of streams,
但显然这不是循环，因为我们没有针对流进行显式循环，
but if you want to have the idea of having values from
但是如果您想从中获取价值
1 to let's say 10 then you can do that with range
1比方说10，那么您可以使用范围
and rangeClosed. If you use range
和范围关闭。如果使用范围
and specify 1 and 10 you'll get the numbers 1 through 9,
并指定1和10，您将获得数字1到9，
because it's exclusive of the final value. If you use rangeClose from 1 to
因为它不包括最终值。如果您使用范围从1到
you get the values from 1 to 10 because it's inclusive
您会得到1到10之间的值，因为它是包含在内的
of the end value.
最终值。
There is also the ability to create a
也可以创建一个
an infinite stream using generate,
使用generate的无限流
where you can simply specify the supplier as Lambda
您可以在其中简单地将供应商指定为Lambda
expression as to how to create values
关于如何创造价值的表达
and the stream will then just be populated with the values based
然后该流将仅填充基于
on what the IntSupplier does. And you can also
IntSupplier的功能。你也可以
iterate, so if you want to apply function let's say
迭代，所以如果要应用函数，可以说
you want to create squares
你想创建正方形
then you can do that starting with 1 or 2
那么您可以从1或2开始
and the using a IntUnaryOperator which just squares the number
并使用一个IntUnaryOperator来将数字平方
so every time you call it, it will provide the next square in the sequence
因此，每次您调用它时，它将提供序列中的下一个正方形
and so on. To Summarise section 4
等等。总结第4节
there is numerous places where you can get stream sources from.
在很多地方都可以从中获取流源。
There is a number of quite useful methods are being added;
现在添加了许多非常有用的方法。
things like being able to retrieve the lines from a file, files from compressed
能够从文件中检索行，从压缩文件中检索文件
archives and so on.
档案等。
The only way to directly create
直接创建的唯一方法
parallelStream is from the collection class but as I say,
parallelStream来自集合类，但正如我所说，
in lesson 3 we will talk about how you can convert from a sequential stream to a
在第3课中，我们将讨论如何从顺序流转换为
parallel stream and talk about the issues around that. But
并行流，并讨论与此有关的问题。但
in terms of creating a stream source only the collection can
就创建流源而言，只有集合可以
create a parallelStream directly. This is the end
直接创建一个parallelStream。这就是结局
of section 4.
第4节。